Kostas **Pagratis**

SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER

2061 Sicily Cir. Longmont CO, 80503

【 (303) 817-1605 | **■** kostas@pagratis.us | **m** kostas-pagratis-7485a14

Summary_

Highly motivated and experienced software engineer with experience in management and deployment of Software Engineering projects including requirements definition, solutions design, implementation, maintenance, testing, support, deployment, enhancements, decommissioning, and final delivery. Knowledgeable in managing multi-functional development teams while utilizing Agile methodologies. Innate ability to adapt to new technologies, architectures, and solutions while striving to ensure code quality and Engineering best practices. Skilled collaborator with years of pair-programming experience and a phenomenal addition to your team culture.

Skills_

Recent Scala, Java, JavaScript, Python, Distributed Systems, Kafka, Git, REST, SQL

Past Rust, AWS, GCP, Unix Scripting, Ant, Maven, C, C++, React, Redux, AngularJS

Work Experience _____

Twitter Boulder, CO

Sr. Software Engineer Oct. 2015 - Present

- Developed an embedded MySQL testing framework now included in finagle and finatra OSS projects facilitating embedded integration testing for MySQL solutions. Additionally developed internal enhancements to seamlessly integrate with build and CI systems used at Twitter. Drove widespread adoption by migrating users and liaising with teams to prioritize efforts.
- Headed a team responsible for implementing an org-wide migration to Bazel while advising teams on how to best tackle issues related to the effort.
- Delivered widespread code health improvements across all of Twitter's code including upgrading mockito across thousands of tests.
- Full stack development of Twitters developer platform encompassing all levels of the technology stack from backed service development to front end React/Redux front end.
- Developed a bulk compliance solution to help Twitter data customers keep large datasets in compliance.
- Mentored junior developers and interns from new hire to first promotions.

Flatirons Solutions Boulder, CO

TECHNICAL LEAD May 2008 - Oct. 2015

- Led various teams tackling custom digital asset management projects across multiple sectors.
- Implemented global portal for Disney Consumer Products customers to acquire digital assets while improving processing times by multiple orders of magnitude.
- Implemented a test authoring and compilation system for Cambridge Assessments and supported the project through the entire lifecycle starting at in depth data-modeling and discovery through final delivery and support.
- · Modernized Boeing's technical writing apparatus with a new bespoke solution built upon partner technologies.

Rogue Wave Software Boulder, CO

CONSULTING ENGINEER II

Aug. 2005 - May 2008

- Provided on site consulting with customers for requirements gathering, design specification, solution installation, testing, and debugging.
- Ported RogueWave products between various operating systems and compilers including but not limited to RedHat, Solaris, HP-UX, and IRIX, gcc, SunPro, HPaCC, and XLC.
- Established expertise and comfort with exploring and debugging unfamiliar code-bases.

Education

University of Colorado

Boulder Colorado

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

November 10, 2022 Kostas Pagratis